爸
Hey, Pop.
凯文·安德伍德
好久不见啊
Been a while, hasn't it?
看到车队驶过来了吗
Did you see that motorcade roll up?
这是首次有美国总统
It's the first time that the President of the United States
来到加夫尼
has visited Gaffney.
你能相信吗
Can you believe it?
如果有的选  我也不会来
Oh, I wouldn't be here if I had a choice.
但我现在得做这种事了
But I have to do these sort of things now.
让我显得更有人情味
Makes me seem more human.
做总统就得有点人情味
And you have to be a little human when you're the president.
他都没钱给自己买墓碑
He couldn't even afford to pay for his own gravestone.
我用自己桑蒂诺军事学院的奖学金买的
I paid for it out of my own scholarship money from The Sentinel.
他葬礼那天只有我去了
Nobody showed up for his funeral except me.
我母亲都没去
Not even my mother.
但我要告诉你  爸
But I'll tell you this, though, Pop:
等我下葬的时候  绝不会是葬在自家后院
when they bury me, it won't be in my backyard.
等人们前来吊唁的时候
And when they come to pay their respects,
他们得排队
they'll have to wait in line.
你该让我们在墓地拍张照
You should let us take a photo at the grave.
他想要点隐私  他可是在给父亲扫墓啊
He wants privacy. The man's honoring his father, for God's sakes.
翻译   草草
翻译   国士章鱼X
翻译   肉松富士
翻译   痒痒
翻译   鱼小姐啦
时间轴   aaaBao
后期   饿得慌
顾问   老杜
鸣谢   忙成狗的网飞
鸣谢   阿小小海
特效   草草
校对   草草
总监   草草
纸牌屋
第三季  第一集
这是你要的信息
Here's the info you were looking for.
我们把那个安排在了下周二早上10点
And we have that scheduled for next Tuesday at 10 a.m.
没问题吧
That's still good for you, right?
很好  我会确认的
Excellent. I'll confirm it.
抱歉
Excuse me.
什么事  先生
Yes, sir?
是  先生
Yes, sir.
总统可以见你了
The president is ready to see you now.
天呐
Jesus.
我伤心欲绝
I'm devastated.
我爱他如子
I love this man as if he were my son.
他是个斗士  我相信他能挺过来
Now, he's a fighter, and I'm sure that he'll pull through.
我们都为他祈祷
Our prayers are with him.
"...安德伍德总统昨日在一场新闻发布会上如是说
"...said President Underwood during a press conference yesterday.
马里兰州警方
The Maryland State Police
和联邦有关部门尚未找到
and Federal authorities have yet to locate
斯坦普先生的车或提出任何嫌疑人"
Mr. Stamper's car or name any suspects."
还想听吗  弟弟
You want more of this, brother?
或许听听体育版吧
Or maybe the sports page?
"世界职业棒球大赛第六场比赛
"Game Six of the World Series
连续13局未得分
went scoreless for 13 innings
紧接着又因大雨延迟
before a rain delay
使这个已具有史诗性的夜晚
that turned an already epic evening
足以载入史册"
into one for the history books."
心思与你同在
弗兰克
克莱尔
美国总统
第一夫人
31号病房需要医生
We need a doctor in room three-one.
道格拉斯
Douglas?
能听到吗
Can you hear me?
如果能听到眨下眼睛
I want you to blink if you can hear me.
再来
Again.
我是兰吉维尼医生
My name is Dr. Lanjwani.
总统办公室要求我亲自看护你
The president's office asked me to look after you personally.
你能得到最好的护理  好吗
You're getting the very best of care, okay?
道格拉斯  如果你能感觉到  就眨眼睛
Douglas, I want you to blink if you can feel this.
很好  很好
Good. Good.
这样呢
How about this?
好的  很好
Okay. Excellent.
这样呢
And this?
这里呢
How about here?
放松
Relax.
放松  早期阶段这很正常
Relax. Perfectly normal at this early stage.
放松
Relax.
很好
That's good.
好的  休息吧
Okay. Get some rest.
你是不是要伤害我
Are you gonna hurt me?
你让我干什么都行  求你别伤害我
I will do whatever you want, please just don't hurt me.
-疼吗  -有点
- Does that hurt? - A little.
好了  我们开始吧  握拳
All right, let's go ahead. Try and make a fist for me.
-雷米  -什么
- Remy. - What's that?
雷米·丹顿  他在吗
Remy Danton. Was he here?
他来过  来看你怎么样了
He was. Just checking on your progress.
来  握个拳
Go ahead, make that fist for me.
狮子
Lion.
犀牛
Rhinoceros.
-骆驼  -很好
- Camel. - Good.
鲁道夫的鼻子什么颜色
What color is Rudolph's nose?
-鲁道夫  -驯鹿
- Rudolph? - Reindeer.
红色
Red.
是红色的
It's red.
美国总统
The President of the United States?
道格拉斯
Douglas?
美国总统是谁
Who is the President of the United States?
弗兰克·安德伍德
Frank Underwood.
-今年是哪年  -2014年
- What year are we in? - 2014.
几月份
What month is it?
12月
It's December.
我得回去工作
I have to get back to work.
道格拉斯  听我说
Douglas. Listen to me.
你遭受了有创骨折...
You suffered a compound fracture--
我知道我什么毛病
I know what I fucking suffered!
你好好听我说
I need you to hear me this time.
你左额皮质遭到了损伤
There was damage to your left frontal cortex.
你的运动技能将有退化
Your motor skills will be a struggle.
你将情绪多变
Your emotions will be unpredictable.
前面的路很长  我们不能心急
There's a long road ahead, and we can't rush it.
-我们稍后做测试吧  -不
- Let's do the test later. - No.
现在就做完
We'll finish it now.
你母亲叫什么
What was your mother's name?
她年轻漂亮
She was young and beautiful.
雅各在她照看羊喝水时爱上了她
Jacob fell in love with her while she was watering a lamb, and...
他做了七年的工
she became his wife after he worked seven years
才终于娶到她
to earn her hand in marriage.
推  脚跟向我手里使劲
Push back. Heel into my hand.
呼吸
Breathe.
归位  深呼吸  准备好了吗
Back up. Deep breath. Ready?
推  用力
Push. Push.
道格
Doug.
集中注意
Focus.
我今天递交国会的报告
The report I submit to Congress today
所包含的证据
includes evidence that
通常足以展开刑事检控
would normally warrant criminal prosecution,
但鉴于总统特赦
but the Justice Department won't pursue charges
司法部不会提出起诉
in accordance with the presidential pardons.
我很感激邓巴女士及其团队
I'm grateful for the hard work Ms. Dunbar and her team
对此次调查的尽心尽力
have dedicated to their investigation.
作为回应  我将组建跨党派委员会
In response, I'll be forming a bipartisan commission
研究竞选筹款改革  以确保历史不再重演
to examine campaign finance reform so history does not repeat itself,
也让我们国家愈合伤口
and so that our nation can heal from these wounds.
我有培根芝士和普通的  你要哪种
I got bacon-cheese and regular. Which one you want?
等等
Just a minute.
还记得你以前从不吃
Remember when you'd never eat a burger
没有培根的汉堡吗
if it didn't have bacon on it?
爸会发火
Dad would get so pissed
因为他讨厌烤培根油的味儿
because he hated the smell of bacon grease on the grill.
我在听呢  加里
I'm trying to listen, Gary.
总统也没办法  就让他去死[烧]吧
The president's hands are tied. Might as well let him burn.
改革不止需要一个委员会
他们在准备棉花糖了
They're getting their marshmallows ready.
看看安德伍德的支持率
Look at Underwood's approval rating.
比沃克辞职之前的还糟
It's worse than Walker's before he resigned.
要从那个坑里爬出来  会很不容易
That's a deep, deep hole to climb out of.
共和党会得意一阵了
The Republicans are gonna have their fun for a while.
普选时有很多可以拿来打击他的东西
Plenty to hammer him on in the general.
而且他们一心想伤人见血
And they're out for blood.
教育和福利改革他们都输得很惨
They lost big on education and entitlement reform.
还有  如果那些关于
And if the rumors
《美国就业法案》的传言是真...
about America Works are true...
这计划对左派太右
For the left, that's just too far to the right
对右派太左
and for the right, it's too far to the left.
他们需要我回去
They need me back.
哪里  白宫吗
Where? The White House?
我们得扭转局势  开始为2016造声势
We got to turn the corner, start ramping up for 2016.
他或许能扭转乾坤呢
He might turn this around.
你不是真觉得他会赢吧
You don't really think he's gonna win, do you?
他经验丰富  安德伍德有很多...
The guy's experienced. Underwood has a lot...
他会恢复的
He'll recover.
他是个幕后推手
He's a behind-the-scenes guy.
他在聚光灯下不自在
He's not comfortable in the spotlight.
不如你先恢复吧
How about you recover first?
...假意热情  亲吻婴儿
...glad-handing and kissing babies.
如果这证明了什么  就是这18个月会很漫长
This is gonna be a long 18 months if this proves any indication.
会许下一堆空头承诺
It can be a lot of chest-thumping
但却毫无建树
but nothing really getting done.
解忧灵有助缓解抑郁症
The Xybenetrin will help with depression.
丁螺环酮是治疗焦虑的  给你
The buspirone is for anxiety. Here you go.
我想给你开点止疼药  但鉴于你的...
I'd like to prescribe you something for the pain, but with your...
所有有瘾史的病人...
Well, any patient with a history of addictive behavior--
我懂  没事
I know. It's fine.
疼我撑得住
I can handle the pain.
他看上去好多了
He looks a lot better.
不  他还在睡呢
No, he's still asleep.
我得挂了
I have to go.
好
Okay.
打扰你了吗
Is this a bad time?
没有  没事
No. It's fine.
就是没人告诉我你要来
No, it's just no one told me you were coming.
弗兰西斯要我代好
Francis sends his love.
他很想亲自来  但是媒体...
He would visit himself, but with the media...
不  我懂
No, I understand.
他之前来过的  那时...
He did come before, when...
-我们俩都来过  -我知道
- Both of us. - I know.
我看到花了  谢谢
I saw the flowers. Thank you.
-你看上去挺好  -我在好起来了
- You look well. - I'm getting there.
我只想好起来  好回去工作
I just want to get better so I can get back to work.
我们都盼着呢
We're looking forward to that.
我们真是需要一切帮助
We can use all the help we can get, actually.
嗯  我一直在看新闻
Yeah. Been watching the news.
弗兰西斯  他真是无计可施了  共和党...
Francis, he's at his wit's end. The Republicans...
不肯给他一张他能签的法案
won't send him a single bill he can sign.
-民主党也好不到哪去  -鲍勃·博奇
- And the Democrats aren't much better. - Bob Birch?
瞎子给蠢货带路
Blind leading the stupid.
雷米干得还好吗
How's Remy working out?
我们更希望是你在  但他还不错
Well, we'd much rather have you there, but he's doing a fine job.
道格  你...记得什么吗
Doug, do you... recall anything?
-关于事发经过  -怎么
- About what happened? - Why?
警察有什么发现吗
Did the police find something?
据我们所知是没有
Not that we're aware of.
我们叫他们暂时不要讯问你
And we've asked them to hold off questioning you
直到你感觉好一些
until you're feeling more like yourself.
瑞秋  她...
Rachel, she...
我不记得了
I don't remember.
不  你记得
Yes, you do.
是劫车
A carjacking.
-是个男人  -什么样的男人
- A man. - What sort of man?
那部分记不清了
That part's fuzzy.
那就可能是任何人了  谁都可能
It could be anyone, then. Any man.
是啊  谁都可能
Yeah. Any man.
他被吓跑了吗
And he got frightened?
我去追他  然后就记不得了
I chased him and that's all.
知道她在哪吗
Any idea where she is?
不知道
No.
我们一定得找到她
Because it's important that we find her.
我真不知道
I really don't know.
真的
That's the truth.
你把这些都告诉警察
I want you to tell all of this to the police,
你跟我说的原话
exactly what you told me,
关于劫车  那个男人  别提她
about the carjacking and the man. Nothing about her.
知道了
I got it.
你如果需要什么  或记起了什么...
If you need anything, or remember anything...
-见到你真好  -你也是
- It's good to see you. - You, too.
紧急
很好  再来  向上向前  很好
That's good. One more time. Up and forward. That's good.
很好  呼吸
Excellent. Breathe.
很好
Good.
很好  很好
Good. Good.
好了
Okay.
试试这个  你做得很好
Let's try this one. You're doing a great job.
继续呼吸  很好
Keep breathing. Good.
很好  道格
Good job, Doug.
好的  向前来  你行的
Okay. Moving forward. You got it.
很好  很好
Great. Great job.
继续
Keep going.
很好  呼吸
Good. Breathe.
很好  不错
Excellent. Good.
再来一个
One more.
很好
Great job.
再来一次  就好了  准备好了吗
One more time. It's almost done. Ready?
保持呼吸
Keep breathing.
只记得他的声音  他说"下车"
Just his voice. He said, "Get out of the car."
能描述一下他的声音吗
Anything you can say about the voice?
形容下口音  咬字  音调高低
Was it, uh... Accent? Lisp? High? Low?
深沉
Deep.
就记得这些了
That's all I remember.
然后我鸣了笛
Then I laid on the horn. I...
我记得他跑了
I remember him running.
很模糊  我下了车
Like a blur, I got out.
去追他
I chased him.
我也不确定  我一定...
I'm not sure. I must have...
你去马里兰州那里做什么
What were you doing in that part of Maryland?
斯坦普先生
Mr. Stamper?
先生  你去马里兰州那里做什么
Sir. What were you doing in that part of Maryland?
我有时候会开车思考
I drive sometimes to think.
当时工作上有很多事
There was a lot on my mind with work.
我只是开车清理思绪
I drive to clear my head.
你们找到车了吗
Have you found the car?
我们目前只有你刚刚提供的信息
We don't have anything other than what you just told us.
你的情绪最近如何  有过情绪爆发吗
How's your mood been? Any episodes?
没有  药物很好使
No. The meds are working.
你只是跟我说好听的吗
You just telling me what I want to hear?
不是  我感觉不错
No. I feel good.
好
Okay.
我今天就批准你出院
I'm gonna sign your release today.
但你一开始一定别太急躁
But it's important you take it easy at first.
一切都会变得难很多
Everything's gonna be much harder in general.
我知道
I know.
有人能照顾你吗
Do you have someone who can look after you?
有  我哥哥加里从俄亥俄州过来了
Yeah. My brother Gary's in from Ohio.
很好  他能待多久
Good. How long is he here for?
-能待一阵吧  -好的  很好
- A while, I guess. - Okay, great.
你一定要去参加互助会
It's important you go to your meetings.
继续保持不沾酒
Stay on top of your sobriety.
拿着这个  用来注射给你开的类固醇
Take this. It's for the steroids I prescribed you.
每周一次  一针打在右腿大腿上
It's one shot into the right thigh, once a week.
护士...
The nurse, she...
-她教过我了  -好
- She showed me how. - Okay.
欢迎回家
你做的吗
You do this?
不  不是我
No, it wasn't me.
我们找人打扫了
觉得该让你回到整洁的家中
冰箱里有足够吃的
弗兰克和克莱尔
我跟我上司谈过了
I talked to my boss.
你过渡期间  我可以
I can stick around for another couple of weeks
再留两周
while you transition back.
你该回你家人那里
You should get back to your family.
没事  萨拉不介意
Nah... Sarah's fine with it.
孩子们也是
The kids are, too.
加里  我们都十年没怎么通话了
Gary, we've hardly spoken in ten years.
你已经做了很多了
You've already gone above and beyond.
好吧  你要我走吗
All right. You want me to go?
我没事了
I'm fine.
多谢你做的一切
Thanks for everything.
好吧
Okay.
有事打给我  我立刻坐飞机过来
I mean, I'm just a phone call and a plane ticket away.
一路顺风
Safe travels.
保重
Take care.
加里
Hey, Gary, I...
给我寄点孩子的照片来
Send me some pictures of the kids.
嗯  好
Yeah, I will.
我欣赏你的一点
But one of the things I admire about you
是在华盛顿特区
is that in Washington, DC,
效率这么低的地方  你总能办成事
which is so gridlocked, you get things done.
据我所知  你有一项新的法案
And I understand you've got, um, a new piece of legislation,
你要推出一项重要的新法案  是什么
a major new initiative you're rolling out. What is it?
没错
That is correct.
是一项新就业计划  《美国就业法案》
It's a new jobs program that we're calling America Works.
弗兰西斯·J·安德伍德  美国总统
那么是奇幻小说喽
So it's a fantasy novel.
这项法案从根本上
This is a fundamentally different look
重新审视了解决就业问题之道
at how to solve the problem of unemployment.
它有罗斯福新政的规模和深度
It has the size and the scope of the New Deal.
那么说是社会主义的财富重新分配政策喽
So it's a socialist redistribution of wealth
让婴儿潮一带像七鳃鳗一样吸住千禧一代wherein the baby boomers will latch onto the millennials like a lamprey
分别指46年至65年出生的人和80年至00年出生的人
一直到把他们吸干为止
and just keep sucking until they're as dry as a crouton?
这项法案旨在促进就业
This is about putting people to work
完全避免福利政策
and avoiding the entitlements entirely.
这我喜欢
Well, I like the sound of that.
怎么  我们要让私营公司经营社保
So what, we're gonna privatize Social Security
然后靠把老人赶尽杀绝提高税收吗
and then raise revenue by hunting the elderly for sport?
-好计划  就这么办  -不  我说了
- Good plan. Use that. - No, as I said,
这是一种全新的方式
this is a fundamentally different approach entirely.
你觉得国会的
And you think that the Republicans
共和党人会配合你吗
in Congress will cooperate with you?
我想事实已经证明
Oh, I think that it has been proved
两党的心愿是一致的
that both parties want the same thing.
2016年换个总统吗
A new president in 2016?
不  我认为  彻底根除失业
No. No, I think actually, I think unemployment, eradicating it,
和强盛的经济  是两党共同的愿望
and I think a strong economy is something both parties want.
好吧  说到大家的心愿
Okay, speaking of everyone,
路透社最近做了一项民调
there's a recent poll by Reuters.
我要说对了  结果显示  十分之八的美国人
I wanna get this right. It says that eight out of ten Americans
都认为你  缺乏"效率和领导能力"
agree that you lack, quote, "Effectiveness and leadership."
听我说  我不为这样的民调操心
Uh, look, I don't let polls like that bother me.
我觉得等国人看到《美就法》执行
I think that once the nation sees AmWorks in action,
他们的态度就会转变
they will change their attitudes.
什么  "《美就法》"
I'm sorry, "AmWorks?"
抱歉  我还不知道是叫这么个名字呢
I'm sorry-- I didn't realize it was called AmWorks.
听着像安利啊  是传销吗
Is that like Amway? Is it a pyramid scheme?
这就是你向美国人民兜售的吗
Is that what you're selling the American people?
不  只是个缩略语  说起来方便
No, it's actually just an abbreviation to make it easier to say.
如果缩得够小
Well, if you make it small enough,
或许咽回去就更轻松了
uh, maybe it'll be easier to swallow.
要知道  虽然你是民主党人  我还是尊重你
You know, even though you're a Democrat, I respect you.
但我们先看看事实
But let's just take a look at the facts here for a second.
你才做了六个月的总统
You've been president for six months,
我还是...要说对了
and again, I wanna get this right,
失业率上涨了
unemployment has gone up,
我们与中国的贸易逆差也上涨了
our trade deficit with China has increased,
否决数也大幅激增
the number of vetoes has skyrocketed.
我不太确信
I'm not entirely sure that I'm confident
你能像根除你的支持率那样
that you'll be able to eradicate unemployment the same way
有效地根除失业
you've been able to eradicate your approval polls.
要知道...
What, you know, what do you--
你打算怎样让美国人民信服啊
How are you going to get it across to the American people?
道格
Doug?
赛斯
Seth?
嗯  是我
Yeah, it's me.
安德伍德夫人  她给了我这部手机...
Mrs. Underwood, she gave me this phone, but--
我知道  有什么问题吗
I know. Is something wrong?
没有  我想找总统
No. I want to speak to the president.
急事吗
Is it urgent?
我想跟他谈《美国就业法案》的事
I want to talk to him about the America Works program.
那就不是急事喽
So nothing urgent.
对  不紧急
It's not an emergency, no.
因为这电话是仅供紧急情况
'Cause that's what this phone is for.
你能转达下我的请求吗
Will you pass on my message?
你来迟了
You're late.
我换了三辆出租车
I switched cabs three times.
-你被人跟踪了吗  -不想抱侥幸心理
- Were you being followed? - Didn't want to take chances.
你知道我叫你来做什么
You know why I asked you here.
我不知道她在哪
I don't know where she is.
那你就给我找到
Then you need to find out.
我查了她的社保号  名字
I ran her social, her name,
警方记录  税务记录  都查了
police records, taxes, everything.
她说不定被哪个嫖客丢在阴沟里了
She could be tossed in a ditch by a john for all I know.
-你在联调局工作  -有我什么好处
- You work at the FBI. - What do I get in return?
我的保护  如你所说
My protection, like you asked.
我以为你真有什么  货真价实的东西
I thought you had something to offer. Something real.
钱吗
Like money?
比如帮我脱离联调局
Like getting me out of the Bureau.
你实现这一点  我或许能帮你
You make that happen, maybe I can help you.
说好的条件是撤销对你的指控
That was a condition, for your charges being dropped.
瞧  你现在没人脉了
See, you don't still know people.
我就不该来
I shouldn't have even come here.
我是你唯一的安全保障
I am your only safety net.
你以为我会交出那些美国电话电报公司的记录
You think I would have turned over all the AT&T records
而不给谁留个备份吗
without leaving a backup with somebody?
我不会为了无用功报销我的免牢金牌
I'm not gonna blow my get-out-of-jail card on a wild goose chase.
有人起疑吗
Does anyone suspect anything?
联调局那边
At the Bureau?
没人知道她
Nobody has a clue about her.
如果能让你安心的话
If that gives you any peace of mind.
道格
Doug?
告诉他是急事
Tell him it's urgent.
我们希望能安排在五月
We're aiming for sometime in May.
我们一跟俄国代表团敲定日期
As soon as we agree on a date with the Russian delegation,
就马上告诉你  格雷格
you will be the first to know. Uh, Greg.
与佩特罗夫在华盛顿的峰会
The Summit with Petrov here in Washington,
会谈重点将是什么
what'll be the focus of the talks?
对中东采取的双边政策
A bilateral approach to the Middle East.
你也知道  以色列军队不撤离约旦河谷
As you know, the Palestinians have refused to negotiate
巴勒斯坦就拒绝谈判
until Israeli troops leave the Jordan Valley.
我们希望与佩特罗夫总统商议此事
We hope to address this with President Petrov
也好继续谈很多其他问题
so that we can move on to a whole host of other issues.
萨拉
Sara.
那么这项政策的商议不包含以色列和巴勒斯坦
So this bilateral approach doesn't include Israel and Palestine.
国务院在向所有相关方做简报
The State Department is briefing all interested parties.
峰会只是第一步  艾拉
The summit's really just a first step. Ayla.
我想就《美国就业法案》提问
I'd like to change course to the America Works program.
请问
Please.
我采访了多位总统政策顾问
I've spoken to a number of the president's policy advisors,
他们说经济团队在这项就业计划
who say there's been a lot of disagreement on the economic team
该采取何种形式方面有很多分歧
as to exactly what form this jobs package should take.
-哪些顾问  -想得美
- Which advisors? - Nice try.
我要说明  这并不仅仅是一项就业计划
To be clear, this is far more than just a jobs package.
是一项全面的计划
It is a comprehensive plan,
其目的是两年内实现全面就业
which aims at full employment within two years.
就此而言  还有很多细节问题有待解决
So as such, there are a lot of details to be worked out.
所以你的消息来源不准确
So your sources are inaccurate.
并非是什么分歧
It's not so much a disagreement
而是就计划细节进行辩论  杰西
as it is debating the finer points of the plan. Jess.
我想再追问一句  都有些什么细节问题
Just to follow up. What are some of the finer points?
甚至是计划大致是如何
Or the broad strokes, even.
白宫没有任何人透露任何信息
No one from the White House has said anything.
等我们能拿出计划  我们就会拿出来
When we have a plan to present, we will present it.
杰西
Jess?
《美国就业法案》是否是
Is America Works a reaction
针对总统低支持率的举措
to the president's low approval ratings?
为给竞选造势  而向民众展现政绩
An effort to offer some sign of progress ramping up to the elections?
我们从第一天就开始准备这项法案了
We've been working on this plan since day one.
这与支持率毫无关系
It has nothing to do with the approval ratings.
但至于选举  今天该谁问了
But as for the election... uh, whose turn is it to ask today?
-马克  -总统会参加2016年竞选吗
- Mark? - Is the president running in 2016?
今天  重点是好好执政  但是...
Today, the priority is good government, but...
明天接着问吧
Ask me again tomorrow.
谢谢大家
Thank you, everyone.
10点钟有个空窗
We've got a window at ten.
我这就打给他
I'll call him now.
请坐
Please, sit down.
约翰  萨曼莎
John. Samantha.
你们跟记者说我们这屋里出现的分歧了吗
You spoke to a journalist about disagreements in this room?
再发生一次  你们就走人吧
If that happens again, you're off the team.
说到这屋里出现的分歧
And speaking of the disagreements in this room,
我们现在出现了更大的分歧
we now have an even bigger one,
雷米给我看了你们目前的成果
because Remy has shown me your work so far and...
无力
it's toothless.
我三个月前站在这间屋子里
I stood in this room three months ago
给你们下达了明确的指令
and gave you all very clear direction.
社会保险  医疗保险  医疗补助
Social Security, Medicare, Medicaid,
所有这些在吸干国库的福利项目
every entitlement program that is sucking us dry,
全都放在桌上
I want it all on the table.
这还远远不够
And this doesn't go nearly far enough.
所以我们显然是得回到一些基本问题上了
So we obviously have to get back to some basics.
回顾一些摆在我们面前的事实
Remind ourselves of some of the facts that are before us--
-先生  我能...  -不不不
- Sir, if I may-- - No, no, no, no.
我先说  然后你再说  保罗
I will speak first, and then you will speak, Paul.
这是国民一年平均从福利项目
This is what the average senior citizen gets,
得到的数额
one year from entitlements,
不管是清洁工  还是对冲基金经理
whether they were a janitor or they ran a hedge fund.
这笔钱  就是一份
That-- This money is a job
我们本可给一位单身母亲
we could be giving to a single mother
或应届毕业生的工作
or a student just out of school.
现在呢
Now, at the moment,
每一元的税中有44美分流向了这些项目
44 cents of every tax dollar goes to pay for these programs.
到2030年  就将超过一半  62美分
By 2030, it'll be over half, 62 cents.
福利项目在让国家破产
Entitlements are bankrupting us.
我让雷米进行了一项民调
Now, I had Remy conduct a little poll.
提出陈述为  "做对国家有益的事
Statement posed was: "Doing what's best for my country
等于做我不喜欢的事"
means doing some things that I don't like."
74%的人认同这一陈述
Seventy-four percent agreed with this statement.
74%  这说明什么
Seventy-four percent. Now, what does that tell us?
我们必须做人们不会喜欢的事
We have to do the things that people won't like.
即便我们做了
And even when we do,
也会有四分之三的人支持我们
three out of four of them will go along with us.
为什么  因为我们能保证就业
And why? Because we're promising jobs.
再说一遍  我们要在哪三个领域
And again, where are the three areas
创造就业呢
that we're gonna be creating these jobs from?
州和联邦基础建设项目
Infrastructure at the state and federal level.
扩大军队
Increasing the size of the military,
并与私营部门合作
and working with our friends in the private sector to start--
抱歉  先生  我必须打断
I'm sorry, sir, but I have to interrupt.
你要削减或砍掉的项目
The programs that you want to scale back or dismantle
是美国梦的基石啊
are the bedrock of the American dream.
工作努力  交税
You work hard, you pay your taxes--
不  抱歉  那曾是美国梦的基石
No, I'm sorry, they were the bedrock of the American dream.
但现在不是了
But they're not anymore.
尤其是对那失业的一千万人来说
Certainly not for the ten million people who are out of work.
但从实际角度出发  数千特殊利益群体
But practically speaking, a thousand special interests,
工会  两党都有反对声音
organized labor, opposition in both parties.
我们可以就你的提议折中一下...
Now, we can do a version of what you're proposing--
我不要折中
I don't want a version.
我要远大愿景
I want a vision.
作为团队领袖  我认为我可以代表所有人说
As head of this team, and I think I speak for everyone,
-我们已经...  -作为总统
- we have done-- - Speaking as the president,
我选择了这支团队  你们为我工作
who chose this team and for whom it works,
我要拿到五千亿美元
I want five hundred billion dollars
给一千万民众工作
to put ten million people to work.
我不管这多让人肉疼
I don't care how much it hurts.
我不管这有多具争议性
I don't care how controversial it is.
你们的职责  就是找出办法
Your job is to find a way.
说服国会和美国人民是我的工作
It's my job to convince Congress and the American people.
你们的工作不是向我推销你们的妥协方案
Your job is not to sell me on your version of my program.
大家都清楚自己该做什么了吗
Now, are we all clear on what our jobs are?
很好  因为我要在30天内
Good, because I want to present this proposal
向领导层呈递这份提议
to leadership in 30 days.
-我们实现这个目标吧  -保罗
- Let's make it happen. - Paul?
-我们不再需要你了  -什么
- Your services are no longer needed. - Excuse me?
别声张  保持和气
Let's keep it quiet, let's keep it cordial.
-多谢你的辛劳  -我去收拾东西
- Thanks for all your work. - I'll get my things.
我会叫人给你送到大厅的
I'll have them sent down to you in the lobby.
喂
Hello?
好的  马上就来
Yeah. I'm on my way.
天啊
God!
请您稍等几分钟  请坐
It'll be a few minutes. Please, have a seat.
-你知道多久了  -两个月
- How long have you known? - Two months.
我作为法官的能力尚未受到影响
It hasn't impaired my judgment on the bench.
而且目前只是早期
And it's early on.
还要一段时间才会有一些明显的症状
We don't expect any real symptoms for quite some time.
暂时我还不会穿着
I won't be wandering around the Supreme Court
短裤在最高法院乱晃
in my boxer shorts anytime soon.
但是我想现在就趁早退休  别到那一步
But I'd like to retire now, long before we get there.
大法官  我非常感谢你能有勇气来
Well, Justice, I want to thank you for having the courage
告知我这个消息
to come and share this news with me.
你确定诊断无误吗
Are you sure the diagnosis is correct?
我的医生就是给副总统夫人看病的那位
My doctor's the same that treated the Vice President's wife.
他是美国最厉害的老年痴呆专家
He's the foremost Alzheimer's specialist in America.
是的  我任命唐纳德为副总统了
Yes, I made Donald my vice president.
与其让他在国会惹事  不如放在身边
I'd rather him be a pain in my ass here than over in Congress.
而且就算是共和党员
And even the Republicans
也不能拒绝刚刚经历丧妻之痛的人
couldn't refuse a man who just buried his wife.
玛乔莉走得这么快真是可怕
Terrible how quickly Marjory went.
我现在就告诉你
I'm telling you this now
这样你就有时间考虑一下人选
so you have time to think about candidates
然后我再宣布退休
before I announce my retirement.
-你能给我多长时间  -你需要多长时间
- How much time can you give me? - How much do you need?
我正要向国会提出《美国就业法案》
I'm about to introduce America Works to Congress.
肯定不会轻松
It's sure to be an uphill battle.
还是不要再加个最高法院法官提名来添乱了
And I'd prefer not to add a Supreme Court nomination to the mix.
共和党肯定会拿这个当筹码
The Republicans will just use it as leverage.
我听到了一些风声  要拿福利开刀吗
I've heard rumblings. Entitlements on the chopping block?
所以更需要你继续坐镇
All the more reason to keep you on the bench.
司法部肯定会提出异议
It's sure to be challenged in the Judiciary.
总统先生  我想和我妻子
Mr. President, I want to spend as much time
尽量多在一起
with my wife as possible
趁着我这两年还清醒
in the good years that I have left.
玛乔莉确诊的时候  她也是这么想的
When Marjory was ill, she wanted the same thing.
她离开了史密森尼学会  但是你知道吗
She left the Smithsonian, and you know what?
她在家每一秒都很烦躁  因为不能做事了
She hated every second of being at home, of not being productive,
不能从事自己热爱的事业
of not doing what she loved.
她那段时间过得很艰难
It made her time with us much harder, and...
也非常不开心
it made her deeply unhappy.
工作是最好的调剂  我真希望她当时没退休
Work is the best distraction. I wish she hadn't retired.
而且  她头脑还清楚的时候
And, uh... before she lost her lucid thought,
她说她也很后悔
she said she regretted it, too.
能不能再坚持六个月  最多一年
Can you give me six months? A year at the most? That's all.
让我在应付最高法院的争斗之前
Just enough time to get this program up and running
能有时间让这个法案顺利开展
before I have to face a Supreme Court fight.
-我得考虑考虑  -当然
- I need to think it over. - Oh, of course.
-和你夫人商量一下  -我送你出去
- Speak to your wife. - I'll walk you out.
-研究中心尽快给我落实  -说话算话
- I better get that research center. - Yes, a deal is a deal.
上帝啊  唐纳德  咱们赶紧干活儿吧
Now, good God, Donald, let's get something done.
现在你知道为什么唐纳德会同意了
Now you see why Donald said yes.
他虽恨我入骨
He may hate my guts,
但是再没什么比家庭成员去世
but there's nothing like a death in the family
更能让人识时务了
to separate the wheat from the bullshit.
让他进来吧
Send him in.
是  先生
Yes, sir.
总统可以见你了
The president is ready to see you now.
道格
Doug.
总统先生
Mr. President.
医生告诉我你恢复得很好
The doctor told me your recovery is going very well.
是啊  就是要用这个
Yeah. Well, there's this.
别的地方都恢复如初
But everything else is as good as new.
见到你真是太好了
It's great to see you.
克莱尔和我担心得要死
Claire and I have been worried sick about you.
谢谢你们的礼物
Thank you for the gifts.
也谢谢你们的照顾
For looking out for me.
我没多少亲密的朋友  你是其中之一
I don't have that many close friends. I count you among them.
我很感激你这么说  先生
I appreciate your saying that, sir.
别叫我先生  我们是老朋友了
Oh, drop the "Sir." We're old pals.
嗯
Well...
我才应该道歉
I'm the one who should apologize.
你又给了我个机会  你相信我
You gave me another chance. You trusted me.
这一切我一人承担
And what happened, I take responsibility for that.
让你陷入那种处境
No, for putting you in that position.
别  没这必要
Stop. It's not necessary.
-我让你身陷危机  -没错  但我只在乎
- I endangered you just as-- - Yeah, but all I care about
你还活着  在逐渐恢复
is that you are alive and getting better.
其它的都过去吧
Let the rest of it go.
-你知道我多忠心  -这不用你说
- You know how devoted I am. - You don't have to say it.
你一次又一次地证明了自己
You proved it time and time again.
来  坐下
Now, come on, come on, sit down.
坐在这儿
Right here.
当初有机会时我就该解决了她
I should've taken care of her when I had the chance.
我还没找到她
I haven't found her yet.
等我找到她  一定确保别人再找不到
But when I do, I'll make sure that no one else does.
我向你保证  先生
You can count on that, sir.
你打算怎么办...
How is it, uh...?
我不告诉你可能比较好
Probably better if we don't talk about it.
嗯  是啊
Right, of course.
他们说你要见我
Well, they told me you needed to see me.
先生  我知道这要求很过分
Well, sir, I... I know that it's a lot to ask,
我给我们惹了这么大麻烦
and that I probably don't deserve it,
我或许也不配
considering the mess I put us in.
你肯定也有顾虑
And I'm sure you have your doubts.
我知道我不能明目张胆  但...
I realize it couldn't be anything too visible, but...
我一直在跟进《美国就业法案》的报道
I've been following everything with America Works.
这扯哪去了
Well, that's a ways off.
我觉得我能帮上忙
But I was thinking that I could help.
游说委员会领导层应该有明确目标
There should be a targeted plan for lobbying committee leadership.
我能配合政治团队
And I can work with the political team,
协调国会立法主任和幕僚长
coordinate with House leg directors, chiefs of staff--
我昨天去了加夫尼给我父亲扫墓
I was in Gaffney yesterday, visiting my father's grave.
他从不好好照顾自己
He never took care of himself.
不顾自己心脏有病  最终付出代价
He ignored his heart problems and... he paid the price.
你得尊重自己终有一死的命运  道格
You have to respect your own mortality, Doug.
我不想给你收尸
I don't want to be standing over your grave.
告诉你...
Now, look...
我保证你在这里会有一席之地
There is a place for you here, I promise.
但心急吃不了热豆腐
But we have to go about this slowly.
我在家工作  只跟你和雷米直接接触
I'll work from home. Only direct contact with you or Remy.
要知道你帮我的最好办法
You know the way that you can help me the best
就是好好恢复身体
is to do exactly what you're doing right now,
不要分心
focusing on your recovery.
如果我操之过急
I would never forgive myself
让你压力太大  我绝不会原谅自己
if I put too much on your plate too soon.
没错
You're right.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
谢谢
Thank you.
抱歉  我得走了
I'm sorry, I have to go.
但我说的都是真心话
But look, I meant what I said.
等你准备好了再说
When you are truly ready.
是  先生
Yes, sir.
你想待多久待多久
Stay as long as you like.
三小时前  我们定位到
Three hours ago, we pinpointed him here,
他在也门的夏卜瓦省
in the Shabwa region of Yemen.
配合方面呢
Cooperation?
我几分钟前和外交部长谈过
I spoke to the foreign minister a few minutes ago.
-有多少平民  -二十几个  不明身份
- Civilians? - Two dozen, non-IDs.
太多了
That's too many.
我们担心他可能随时离开
Our concern is that he could be on the move at any moment.
先生  鉴于佩特罗夫要来华盛顿...
Sir, with Petrov coming to Washington--
我们花了两年才找到阿卜杜拉
It's taken us two years to track Abdullah down.
不能为了峰会就放弃一切机会
We can't ignore every opportunity between now and the summit.
你们看到村子情况了吗
Do you have eyes on the village?
是的  先生
Yes, sir.
他就在这栋房子里
He's in this building here.
50米内不留活口
Kill zone is anyone within 50 meters.
如果没有平民伤亡就能除掉他
If we take him out with no civilian casualties,
我就同意这次袭击
I'll authorize the strike.
先生  恕我冒昧  我真心认为
Sir, if I may, I really think--
还有不到两个月佩特罗夫总统就将来访华盛顿
President Petrov is coming to Washington in less than two months.
我们整个中东政策都靠这次峰会
Our entire Middle East policy hinges on that meeting.
如果可能  我们不想给穆斯林社会任何
We don't want to give the Muslim community any viable reasons
阻挠进程的借口
to obstruct things if we can avoid it.
想办法不杀死平民就除掉他
So find a way to do this without killing civilians.
非常感谢各位
Thank you all very much.
能单独谈会儿吗  是克莱尔的事
May I have a moment? It's about Claire.
如果你丈夫提名你  我不会手下留情的
If your husband nominates you, I can't pull any punches.
没经验  任人唯亲
Lack of experience. Nepotism.
没错
That's right.
你觉得我太业余
And you think I'm a dilettante.
不  但很多人会这么认为
No. But plenty of people will.
打从弗兰西斯一就职我就在准备了
I've been preparing since Francis took office.
经验的缺乏我会用职业道德补上
What I lack in experience I'll make up for in work ethic.
为什么要当联合国大使
Why Ambassador to the UN?
你作为第一夫人有更大的影响力
You wield far more influence as the First Lady.
那和切实地去做贡献不一样
That's not the same as contributing in a concrete way.
如果我们投票否决了你
If we vote down your confirmation,
你能接受在公众面前丢面子吗
are you comfortable with that sort of public embarrassment?
我知道有这风险
I know that's a risk.
-你2016年会竞选吧  -无可奉告
- You're running in 2016, right? - No comment.
弗兰西斯和我都惊讶于
Francis and I are impressed
共和党人如此支持你
by how the Republicans are consolidating around you.
你会是一个优秀的候选人
You'll make a good candidate.
但不能和总统夫人勾结
Not by linking arms with the president's wife.
如果我搞砸了  这会是有力的竞选广告
If I'm a disaster, it makes for a good campaign ad.
如果我做得好  那你更是无可指摘
If I do a good job, nobody can fault you.
无论如何这都不会影响你2016的竞选
Either way, it doesn't hurt your chances in 2016.
我很感激你在公布消息前先来找我
Well, I appreciate you coming by before going public.
很有风度也很周到
It is classy, and thoughtful.
我不会故意阻碍你的
I won't actively block you.
剩下就靠你自己努力了
The rest is on your shoulders.
谢谢  参议员
Thank you, Senator.
告诉总统我这么做是出于对你的敬意
Tell the president I'm doing this out of respect to you.
我在普选上打败弗兰克前  他都会在我黑名单上
Frank's still on my shit list till I beat him in the general.
好的
I will.
你怎么不立刻过来
Why didn't you come right away?
我有个会面不能错过
I had a meeting I couldn't miss.
该死的华盛顿
Fucking Washington.
-会有些疼  -我知道
- This is gonna hurt. - I know.
这是扑热息痛  能止痛
Here's some Percocet. It'll help with the pain.
我给你开个30天的处方
I'll write you a 30-day prescription.
我不能
I can't.
-我不能...  -什么
- I'm not supposed to-- - What was that?
没事
Nothing.
好了  你可以走了
All right. You're good to go.
-和门多萨谈得如何  -我觉得还不错
- How did it go with Mendoza? - Well, I think.
他会支持你吗
He'll support you?
他不会公开反对
He won't openly fight it.
那可以一大进步
Well, that is a big step forward.
-道格说了什么  -没什么新消息
- How did it go with Doug? - No real news.
你今晚还要在这里睡吗
Hey, are you in here again tonight?
我感冒还没好  不想传染给你
I'm still getting over this cold. I don't want to get you sick.
好吧  别做事做得太晚了
Well, don't stay up with all that too late.
弗兰西斯
Francis?
我们什么时候公布提名
When do we announce the nomination?
听着  我今晚本来不想谈这事
Listen, I wasn't gonna bring this up tonight,
可你得知道国务院那边
but you should know that there are some serious doubts
有很多疑虑
from people at the State Department.
你是说凯茜
You mean Cathy.
还有她的一些手下
And some on her staff.
什么样的疑虑
Like what?
就是"能力不足""身兼两职"之类的
Well, in over your head, wearing two hats, the obvious things.
你是不是不想这么做了才这么说
And are you saying this because you don't want to move forward?
当然不是  我告诉你  是希望你完全明白
Not at all. I'm sharing with you so you fully understand
你要面对的情况
what you're getting into.
我明白
And I do.
或许我们不该着急
Maybe we shouldn't rush this.
-你现在也有疑虑了  -我可没这么说
- You're having doubts now, too. - I didn't say that.
只是你该多考虑考虑这么做
Only you should put more thought into whether
是否对你合适  就是这样
this is the right move for you. That's all.
晚安  弗兰西斯
Good night, Francis.
早日康复
Feel better.
弗兰西斯
Francis.
我想你这周宣布提名的消息
I want you to announce the nomination this week.
我不想等了  没有什么好时机
I don't want to wait. The timing will never be good.
我明明能积攒实战经验
And I don't want to waste time
何必要浪费时间呢
when I can be getting real experience under my belt.
定个日子举办新闻发布会吧
So set a date, hold a press conference, and let's do it.
克莱尔
Claire!
我提到凯茜并不是说我认为
I was not trying to suggest that you not be the ambassador
你不该当大使  我只是...
when I brought up Cathy. I was just--
我们早说好了
We made a deal,
现在你却要食言了
and now you're trying to back away from it.
-不是这样的  -那你就会告诉凯茜
- That is not true. - Then you would've told Cathy
事情就是这样  让她接受
it's happening to make her peace with that.
-没那么简单  -就是那么简单
- It's not that simple. - Yes, it is.
-你是总统  -我不能控制国会
- You're the president. - I can't control Congress.
我想启动两项重要项目
I'm trying to get two major initiatives off the ground
我的每一步行动都将产生影响
and every move I make will have an effect.
我们早在走进白宫之前就已经说定了
We agreed to this before we ever stepped foot in this house.
-我知道我们说定了  -如果我没有
- I know what we agreed to. - How am I supposed to run for office
令人信服的资历  日后我怎么竞选总统
at some point if I don't have a legitimate track record?
我们必须撑过接下来这18个月
We have to survive the next 18 months,
取得点成绩  再说后面的事
accomplish something, and then look ahead.
弗兰西斯  我们还是现实一点
Francis, let's be realistic.
你能否当选总统完全是没准的事
There's no guarantee you'll get elected.
如果你落选  我得有所准备
I need to be prepared if you don't.
你对我还真是有信心啊
You have that much faith in me, do you?
看来比你对我的信心要大
More faith than you have in me, it seems.
我相信你胜过任何人  克莱尔
I believe in you more than anyone, Claire.
那表现出来  提名我
Then show it. Nominate me.
别让我再费口舌说服你
I shouldn't have to convince you.
不是说不说服的事
It's not about convincing.
而是我们得看清当下的政治气候
It's about being honest about the political climate
-我们现在的处境  -我快要年过半百了
- that we find ourselves-- - I'm almost 50 years old.
几十年来我一直当你的贤内助
I've been in the passenger seat for decades.
也该让我自主一回了
It's time for me to get behind the wheel.
必须现在就开始着手  赶在大选之前
That needs to start now. Before the election.
因为谁知道那时会发生什么
Because who knows what will happen?
万一你输了呢
What if you lose?
我不会只当个填座总统的  克莱尔
I will not be a placeholder president, Claire.
我一定会赢  我会名垂青史
I will win. And I will leave a legacy.
你是说我们会名垂青史
You mean we will.
打扰了  先生
Excuse me, sir.
国防部长来电  他说有要事
The Secretary of Defense is on the line. He says it's urgent.
什么事
Yes?
好的
Okay.
我这就去
I'm coming.
等我到了再开始
Not until I get there.
-我马上下去  -好的  先生
- I'll be right down. - Yes, sir.
穿好衣服  我有东西要给你看
Get dressed. I want you to see something.
进来
Come in.
-给  -多谢
- Here. - Thank you.
那好
Okay, great.
去脱吧
Get undressed.
这是怎么回事
How did this happen?
不重要
Doesn't matter.
我来帮你
Let me help you.
让我来
I'll... I'll do it.
我会小心的
I'll be gentle.
不用小心
Don't be gentle.
像这样吗
Like that?
没错
Yeah.
-搞什么鬼  -是波本
- What the fuck? - It's bourbon.
-我  -只是波本而已
- I-- - That's all. It's just bourbon.
-拿着  -我真不想
- Take it. - I really don't want to.
不是用来注射的
Nothing's going through the skin.
我只是想让你
I just want you to squirt it...
把酒射进我嘴里
into my mouth.
好吗  拜托了
Okay? Please.
-那是目标吗  -是的  先生
- Is that our target? - Yes, sir.
总统先生  这次行动是高度机密
Mr. President, this is a highly classified operation--
我授权第一夫人在场旁观行动
I'm clearing the First Lady for this operation.
好的  请原谅  先生
Yes, sir. Forgive me, sir.
随时准备发射  先生
We are armed and ready, sir.
阿卜杜拉就在那些车辆中
Abdullah is in one of those vehicles.
具体哪一辆我们还不清楚
We can't tell which one.
如果他们兵分三路行动的话
If they go in three different directions,
我们将不知道该摧毁哪一路
we wouldn't know where to strike,
如果让他逃回山中
and if he makes it back to the mountains,
我们的卫星就追踪不到他了
we'll lose our satellite track on him.
那些是孩子吗
Are those children?
我不能确定  先生  但有这个可能
I can't say definitely, sir, but they could be.
可以发动打击吗  先生
Do we have authorization, sir?
-行动吧  -执行打击
- Proceed. - Proceed with the launch.
倒计时10秒
And ten seconds.
And five, four, three...
目标已摧毁  先生
Target is destroyed, sir.
谢谢各位
Thank you, everyone.
我还是要提名
I still want it.
那好吧
All right.
2011年夏天  美国总统奥巴马同国会就"债务上限"展开激烈争斗
在谈判中最终败给国会新当选的一批共和党保守派"茶党"的议员
共和党取得了谈判胜利
"债务上限"一役使奥巴马民望大跌  不仅反对派共和党对他不以为然
民主党内也有很多人认为他缺乏领导能力
为挽回民望和政治影响力
奥巴马于2011年9月8日在国会发表全国性讲话
郑重推出《美国工作法案》(American Jobs Act)
该法案拟在不增加预算赤字的情况下
通过不同渠道筹款四千四百七十亿美元  用于创造就业
然而该法案推出后  不仅遭到国会共和党的强烈反对
在民主党占多数的参议院也没得到足够的支持
由于无法在国会得到通过  白宫被迫将这个法案分拆成几个小法案
但是即使委曲求全  分拆后的法案也大都没通过